makerfaire.com 2016-12-12

# Privacy Policy – Maker Media

**Notification of Changes**  
This privacy policy was updated on August 26, 2016. If we change our Privacy Policy, we will post those changes here.

**Purpose and Scope**  
We want to help makers create projects, share ideas, and build a community. To make this happen, we collect some information from our users. Maker Media Inc. understands how important privacy is to our community. The purpose of this privacy policy is to explain what information we collect, how we use it, and what we’re doing to keep it safe. If you have any questions regarding this privacy policy, you can contact us by sending email to [webmaster@makermedia.com](mailto:webmaster@makermedia.com) _._ This policy discloses what information we gather about you when you visit any of our websites or buy product directly from us. It describes how we use that information and how you can control it.

**Types of Information Maker Media Gathers and Tracks**  
Maker Media collects two kinds of information about users: 1) data that users volunteer by signing up to receive news and product information, entering contests, submitting projects, completing surveys, or buying directly from us; and 2) aggregated tracking data we collect when users interact with our websites.

**Personal Information**  
We never sell or rent your email address or other personally identifiable information. We use the personal information you voluntarily provide to send information you’ve requested, to fulfill orders, and to update you on the status of your activities. The specific use of your personal information varies:

  * Newsletters: When you sign up online to receive Maker Media newsletters, we use your email address to distribute the newsletter and administer your account.
  * Events: When you register for a Maker Media event, we will send you email announcements and updates about Maker Media events and conferences.
  * Purchases: When you order directly from us, we add you to our newsletters list and, unless and until you opt out, we’ll send you update emails and other marketing pieces.
  * Contests & Giveaways: When you enter a contest or giveaway, we may ask for your name, address, and email address so we can administer the contest and communicate with entrants about the results.
  * User Generated Content: When you submit a project, a story, or an idea, we ask for your name and email address so we can communicate with you on the status of it, or so we can attribute it to you.
  * Third Parties: We may provide your personal information to third parties we retain to perform functions on our behalf, such as fulfilling orders, processing credit card payments, managing mailing lists, and delivering packages. These third parties are restricted from using your information for any other purpose.

We release personal information when we believe that release is appropriate to comply with the law, or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Maker Media, our users, or others. This may include exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

**Aggregated Tracking Information**  
We analyze visitors’ use of our sites by tracking information such as pageviews, traffic flow, search terms, and click through. We use this information to improve our sites. We also share this anonymous, non-personal traffic and demographic information in aggregate form with advertisers and other business partners. We do not share with advertisers any information that can identify an individual user.

**Cookies**  
A cookie is a small data file that we transfer to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser when you visit our sites. Cookies enable our systems to recognize your computer, so that we can provide you with personalized information and features. We also use cookies to track user traffic patterns and to target user research surveys. On our sites, we and some of our advertisers use a third-party ad server to display ads. These ads may contain or recognize cookies. The ad server receives these cookies, and we don’t have access to them. Information about your visit to an advertiser’s site, such as number of times you have viewed an ad (but not your name, address, or other personal information), is used to serve ads to you on our sites.

You can set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies or to block cookies. If you block cookies, you may not be able to use certain site features or functions.

**Third Party Services**  
We work with third party services to provide services and functions to improve your experience on Maker Media websites and to operate our business. We may disclose certain of the information we collect to third-party service providers that help us manage communications to and from the Maker Media websites and improve website performance. These service providers have privacy policies that restrict them from further disclosing any of your information.

**Creating an Account on MakerSpace**

To submit posts, to comment on other users’ projects, or to follow other users on makerspace.com, you need to have an account. During account creation, we ask you for your real name, location, and email address, and we assign you a user name. Other users can see your real name, username and location, but not your email address.

When you create a profile on MakerSpace, we will send you email informing you of your profile activity, such as new followers. The information we collect about you when you are logged into MakerSpace, such as which projects you like or interests you identify on your profile, helps us recommend content to you. This information and data about your activities on our site may be used in a number of ways, including the following:

  * To improve the content of the MakerSpace site, including by allowing Maker Media editors to consult with readers.
  * To communicate with users about registration and other customer service issues.
  * To promote our products and services.
  * To conduct research surveys.

**Updating Personal Information on MakerSpace**

You can update your profile information and reset your password through the Account Settings page. You cannot change your username, but you can make a new account and manually copy your projects to the new account.

If you want to delete your account entirely, send an email to[ service@makerspace.com](mailto:service@makerspace.com) and include your user name and the email address associated with the account. You will receive a confirmation email at that same address.

**Creating an Account on Makezine.com**

You do not need to create an account to use makezine.com. However, if you wish to comment on a story on makezine.com, you need to login with your Facebook, Twitter, Google or Disqus account in order to use the third party commenting service provided by Disqus.

**Hackster.io White Label Service**

We have entered into an arrangement with Hackster, Inc. who runs the website Hackster.io, to offer our community the ability to publish step-by-step projects under the title Make: Community Projects. When you create an account from [http://community.makezine.com/share](http://community.makezine.com/share/), you will be using Hackster’s service and creating an account with their service.

To create an account, Hackster will request your email. You can also provide your real name and location; however, this information is optional. Hackster also collects information about you when you are logged in, such as which projects you like and which users you have selected to follow. This information, which is shared only with us, may be used in a number of ways, including the following:

  * To allow you to manage your account and projects.
  * To communicate with you the status of your project or other projects submitted by the community.
  * To inform you of new Hackster features or services.
  * To identify you as the project submitter.

**Additional Information Collected by Maker Media**

  * Usage Information: When you use a Maker Media website, our servers will automatically store a limited amount of information about how you use the website. This information includes a number that identifies your computer (the IP address), which pages you visited, and what browser you are using.
  * Analytics: We also collect some data on where you click and which parts of the site you visit using third party analytics tools. This helps us figure out ways to improve the website. Information collected and processed includes the user’s IP address, network location, and geographic location. The analytics acquire all information directly from the user, by installing a cookie (see the section on Cookies, above) on your computer, if you have enabled JavaScript. We do not share any information we collect with any analytics tool provider, and those providers do not collect any personal identifying information about you.
  * MakerSpace User-generated Content: Your MakerSpace projects, comments, and forum posts are stored on the Maker Media, Inc. servers. Other users can see your shared projects, comments, and forum posts, along with your real name and username. We have access to all content stored on the MakerSpace website, and may use it for moderation and other purposes related to administration of the site.

**Additional Ways Maker Media Uses Your Information**

  * We will use your email address to respond to messages you send us or to communicate with you about the Service or your account.
  * If we detect repeated abusive behavior from your account or IP address, we may share your account name, IP address, and the time and content of the abusive behavior with the IP address owner (such as a school or internet service provided).
  * We may use de-identified location, age, gender, and usage data in research studies intended to improve our understanding of how people learn with the Service.
  * If you forget your MakerSpace password, we will ask you to disclose to us your email address so that we can verify your account and send you a new password.

Other than as described above, we do not share personally identifiable information about you with any other person, company, or organization, except (a) as required to comply with our obligations under the law, and (b) for technical reasons, if we are required to transfer the data on our servers to another location or organization.

**Protecting Your Information**

Maker Media has in place physical and electronic procedures to protect the information we collect through the Service. We strictly limit individual access to our servers and the data we store on them. However, as effective as these measures are, no security system is impenetrable. We cannot completely guarantee the security of our database, nor can we guarantee that the information you supply will not be intercepted while being transmitted to us over the Internet.
